Accomplished leader with 30 year history of delivering excellent business results, Building business development partnerships, attracting and developing top talent.

## **Executive Leadership** International Expansion Strategic Planning

#### PROFESSIONAL PROFILE

Senior-level executive with strong track record of driving revenue and profit for multi-billion dollar pharmaceutical company. Comprehensive background in General Management, and in directing Sales, Marketing, Medical, as well as Clinical Development, Regulatory, Manufacturing, Corporate Affairs and Business Development. Demonstrated entrepreneurial skills as Founder and President of e.Lilly Division. International expertise includes delivering nearly \$1 Billion in annual revenue for company's largest international business. Actively led and executed multiple business development deals across geographies. Talent for leading a corporation through complex growth and expansion. Experience interacting effectively with corporate Board of Directors. Deep expertise in pricing and reimbursement negotiations, and interfacing with government representatives and health care payers. Intricate understanding of high-level lobbying.

#### SELECTED PROFESSIONAL HIGHLIGHTS

- ✓ **Created and deployed** Lilly's drug development/regulatory strategy in Japan, reducing drug launch lag from five years to near simultaneous to double the business to \$2 billion
- ✓ Accelerated revenue growth of Corporation's #2 Product from flat to 13% while preparing for and launching multiple new cancer products
- ✓ **Spearheaded Lilly Japan's launch** of multiple major brands, including Cymbalta, Evista, Zyprexa, Alimta, and new insulin formulations, driving industry-leading sales growth
- ✓ **Developed and led board-approved international payer strategy and execution** including global Patient Access to Cancer care Excellence (PACE) initiative and \$170 million in upside due to pricing negotiations
- ✓ **Conceived, researched, and drove** the execution of revitalized corporate brand image across every functional division of the company
- ✓ **Built and directed** Lilly neuroscience/primary care business unit and business-to-business commercial division in the USA

#### PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

ELI LILLY AND COMPANY, INDIANAPOLIS, IN

1985-PRESENT

Vice President, Oncology Commercial Operations/Business Development/Payer (2011-Present), Oncology Business Unit, Indianapolis, IN

Lead entire commercial effort for Oncology in North America, accountable for over \$2 billion in sales. Oversee Lilly Oncology's global franchise brand and all work associated with payer relations and policy. Lead Oncology business development and external R&D efforts globally.

- Accelerated Alimta's growth from flat to 13% since taking over cross-functional commercial responsibilities
- Launched Cyramza for gastric cancer in US market with 250% to target performance and continued to build Lilly's specialty pharmaceuticals business model
- Developed/executed PACE initiative (Patient Access to Cancer care Excellence)
- Responsible for overseeing Oncology business development, alliances with other pharma and biotech companies, and external financing with board level interface
- Transformed Lilly Oncology's customer facing organization across major functions of sales, account management, marketing, medical, clinical and health outcomes

# Corporate Vice President, Global Policy and Pricing/Reimbursement (2008-2011)

International Corporate Affairs, Indianapolis, IN

Led all aspects of international payer marketing and account management execution capabilities. Managed pricing/reimbursement/access strategies for entire portfolio of Lilly compounds from Phase II through commercialization. Oversaw Lilly's healthcare reform strategy for U.S. Markets.

- Delivered \$170 million over plan in revenue due to pricing and reimbursement (2009).
- Improved revenue by \$50 million through critical overhaul to strategy and governance of Lilly's global anti-counterfeiting procedures
- Hired and trained over 100 new Professional account management positions across international markets
- Earned board-level approval and investment for conception and development of Lilly's international payer vision and strategy
- Successfully transformed global public policy operating model characterized by focused, integrated campaign efforts in key markets across the world, including Brussels, Tokyo, and Shanghai

## President, Eli Lilly Japan KK (2003-2008)

Kobe, Japan

Directed Lilly's largest foreign affiliate, with nearly 2000 employees in sales/marketing/medical, research and development, manufacturing, and supporting functions. Chaired PhRMA's Japan-based executive committee, catalyzing regulatory reforms, and opposing price reductions.

- Led growth to nearly \$1 billion in annual revenue
- Delivered 11% net sales and double-digit growth in profits over 5 years, outpacing the Japanese pharmaceutical market by nearly three times
- Created and deployed Lilly Japan's drug development strategy, and reduced drug launch lag from over five years to less than two, setting affiliate to double in size again by 2015
- Spearheaded the launch of multiple major brands, including Evista, Cialis, Alimta, and new insulin formulations
- Drove turnaround for Zyprexa from <10% to over 30% annual growth
- Negotiated and executed nine major business development deals, including co-marketing and out-licensing of major brands, selling legacy assets, and out-sourcing manufacturing strategy
- Developed the board-approved 10-year growth and investment plan
- Ranked as a top 5 growth company for sales of all pharmaceutical companies in Japan
- Increased Lilly's company sales rank from 34 to 22, setting up for move to top 15

# Vice President, Corporate Communications/Lilly Brand (2002-2003)

Indianapolis, IN

- Selected by CEO for 10 month assignment to develop strategy and change management plan to transform and re-launch corporate brand inside the company
- Conceived, researched, and drove the execution of revitalized Lilly's brand image across every functional division of the company

# Founder and President, e.Lilly Division (2000-2002)

Indianapolis, IN

- Successfully created and launched Lilly's first external venture fund leading to formation of three more corporate funds
- Invested in eight businesses and served on two external start-up boards
  - o Founded, incubated, and spun-out new businesses, including InnoCentive, Chorus, and Customer Relation Management initiative
- Awarded e.Business Executive of the Year in 2001
- Built innovative division to explore and implement new business models for core pharmaceutical business

# Vice President, Primary Care/Neuroscience Business Units (1999-2000)

Lilly USA, Indianapolis, IN

- Managed P&L for \$4 billion in sales
- Effectively led largest business unit in general management role, integrating sales, marketing, medical, regulatory, and corporate affairs
- Delivered double-digit portfolio growth across four major blockbuster products: Zyprexa, Prozac, Evista, and Axid
- Successfully led sales strategy development for over 2500 sales reports

## Vice President, Sales and Operations (1998-1999)

Lilly USA, Indianapolis, IN

- Drove nearly \$4 billion in sales through expansion of sales force, meeting plan each year
- Hired and trained 1000 sales reps, managing increase from 2000 to 3000 people
- Designed and led the affiliate initiative to integrate the business-to-business interactions into sales efforts/pull-through with contracted managed care management
- Led and reorganized the marketing fulfillment division
- Directed all sales training and field leadership development for the US business

# **Executive Director, Business-to-Business/Managed Care** (1997-1998)

Lilly USA, Indianapolis, IN

- Designed, executed, and led Lilly's first integrated managed care/contract management division
- Built new leadership team from inside and outside of the company, attracting talent, removing numerous management layers
- Developed account management excellence training programs, and contract management principles, which remain the foundation of the organization today

ADDITIONAL MARKETING AND SALES HISTORY Lilly USA

Area Director, South Central Division (Birmingham, AL)
Market Research Manager (Indianapolis, IN)
Pricing Manager (Indianapolis, IN)
District Sales Manager (State of Virginia)

EDUCATION AND PROFESSIONAL TRAINING

### **DEPAUW UNIVERSITY**

#### BACHELOR OF ARTS DEGREE IN ECONOMICS AND MATHEMATICS

Academic Honors: Graduated Cum Laude Management Fellow: Center for Management and Entrepreneurship

DUKE UNIVERSITY / HARVARD UNIVERSITY **EXECUTIVE MANAGEMENT AND LEADERSHIP TRAINING** 

PROFESSIONAL AFFILIATIONS

#### **Board of Trustees**

DePauw University, Greencastle, IN

### Board of Trustees (2005-2009)

Young Life, Colorado Springs, CO

REFERENCES

Professional references are available upon request.

**Ministry Experience** 

### **Young Life**

- Board of Trustees: 2005-2009
- Founding Committee Chair
  - o Zionsville Young Life: 2000-2003, 2010-Present
  - o Kobe, Japan Young Life: 2004-2008
- Volunteer Leader
  - o North Central HS, Indianapolis, IN: 1983
  - o St. Anne's Belfield HS, Charlottesville, VA: 1985-1987
- Banquet Speaker

## **College Park Church**

- Elder: 2000-2003
- Adult Bible Fellowship Teacher: 2011-2014
- Parenting Ministry Founder/Coordinator/Teacher: 1998-2002
- Member: 1997-Present

#### **Twelve Stones Ministries**

• Founding Board Chair: 2002-2009

### **Campus Crusade for Christ (CRU)**

Conference Speaker: Butler University/Greek Conference

## **Inter-Varsity Christian Fellowship**

■ Bible Study Leader: 1981-1985

## **Church Memberships**

- College Park Church: 1997-Present
- Kobe Union Church: 2003-2008
- Altadeena Valley Presbyterian (PCA) Birmingham, AL: 1994-1997
- Christ Community Church (PCA), Franklin, TN: 1990-1991
- Zionsville Presbyterian Church (PCUSA), Zionsville, IN: 1988-89; 1991-94
- Trinity Presbyterian Church, Charlottesville, VA (PCA): 1985-1987

## **Mission Trips/Service**

- Dallas, TX: Zionsville Presbyterian Church serving poor, illegal immigrants (2008)
- Ulaanbaatar, Mongolia: Habitat for Humanity home building for poor (2005)
- Toalmas, Hungary: Word of Life Bible Camp teaching Bible, sports, English (2000)
- Mainz, Germany: Greater Europe Mission church planting (1983)